Very few members of Congress have been calling for a ceasefire. You are among those who are now
calling for one. We're seeing growing calls even internationally. The French president calling for
it. You've even had people from within the administration on the civil side of things
putting pressure on the administration to call for a ceasefire. Why do you think that has not
happened yet? Why is the administration reluctant to call for a ceasefire? And do you think the
political pressure that is starting to emerge from some of these swing states like Michigan,
perhaps Georgia and elsewhere may get the White House to recalibrate on this issue?
Eamon, I called for a ceasefire 10 days after October 7th, October 17th. And at that time,
there were about 6,000 Palestinians who had been killed. Today, we're up to over 11,000,
40 percent of whom are children. We are seeing hospitals and health centers be targeted. The
UN says, I think, about 23, including the two largest, al-Shifa and Quds, that have been targeted
by Israeli airstrikes. And the pictures are absolutely devastating. Now, I know that what
Hamas did on October 7th, you and I both know that was horrific. It was a terrorist attack. Israel does
have the right to defend itself. But you cannot substitute one war crime for another war crime.
And the reality is that the United States is the largest backer of military aid to Israel. And if
Israel is not willing to do what we are asking Israel to do, which is follow international humanitarian
law, in my mind, it is clearly not doing that, then I think it is time for us to say we are not
supporting offensive military support for Israel. You know, I think it is ludicrous to say that we
can't control what Israel does. It may be true that we can't control the ultimate thing that Israel does.
But what we can control is our involvement in military equipment that is being used to bomb Gaza.
That is just not acceptable. And for those people who think that this is some solution to ending Hamas,
I will just say that experts, and you are, I think, that's why I wanted to come on your show,
Eamon, because you are so knowledgeable about the subject. But there is no chance that we are going
to achieve the goals that even the United States and Israel and everybody wants to see, which is the
hostages returned, Hamas disabled and humanitarian aid into Gaza, and a forward process for Israel and
Palestine to live, Palestinians to live side by side with security. That is not going to happen
with this approach. It needs to change. And the United States is increasingly isolated from the rest
of the world. So it is time for us to call for a ceasefire. I hope that the Biden administration
understands all of the repercussions and ramifications of continuing to support Israel at with without
any conditions, because I think it is very severe internationally and domestically.
I wanted to get your thoughts on how